## **Garrett Everding**

4A Computer Engineering

137 University Ave. W. Waterloo, Ontario gseverdi@uwaterloo.ca github.com/geverding (226) 868-5820

SKILL SUMMARY Strong problem solving and analytical skills

Experienced with organizing a multi-discipline and remote team Comfortable in a constantly evolving and fast-paced environment Effective in a group environment and with minimal supervision

TECHNICAL PROFICIENCY

Languages: Javascript, Scala, Haskell, c

Platforms: Linux, OSX, AWS Software: Vim, Git, LATEX

Technologies: Node.js, Backbone.js, react.js, d3.js, MongoDB, MySQL, Redis

**EDUCATION** 

Candidate for Bachelor of Applied Science, Honours (Coop) Computer Engineering University of Waterloo, Waterloo, Ontario Sept. 2010 - Present

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Software Developer

Jan. 2014 - April 2013

Auvik Networks, Waterloo, ON.

- Rewrote logging service to simplify integration with external logging facilities and internal services
- Prototyped modular UI to allow system administrators to dig into various aspects of their infrastructure
- Implemented basic classifiers to remove extraneous log messages

#### Software Developer

May 2013 - Aug. 2013

Monstercat, Waterloo, ON.

- Developed Javascript heavy web applications for managing a record label and a YouTube network
- Implemented intuitive UI controls to streamline data entry and management
- Played a key role in architectural discussions focused on improving the functionality and maintainability of the system
- Maintained critical production servers

#### Software Developer

Sept. 2012 - Dec. 2012

Monstercat, Waterloo, ON.

- Built real-time, interactive promotional web applications for album releases
- Implemented fluid and intuitive controls for a new record label management system
- Maintained and setup production and development servers for performance driven applications

### **Garrett Everding**

Page 2

#### Software Designer

Jan. 2012 - April 2012

International Datacasting, Ottawa, ON.

- Worked closely with the core software developers to implement new software features and fix bugs
- Developed for the head-end system, which transmits content files to receivers via satellite and terrestrial links
- Implemented new webservice calls for the head-end system to remotely manage customer satellite receivers

## RELEVANT PROJECTS

#### Weird Canada (weirdcanada.com)

Feb. 2014 - Present

- Complete rewrite of site in Haskell and ClojureScript
- Designed REST API to allow third parties to integrate with site

#### WikiWalk (wikiwalk.herokuapp.com)

Feb. 2013

Visualization of The Wikipedia Game

- Generated a tree of interconnected Wikipedia articles given a user specified seed
- Built for the Sortable {data} Hackathon using Node.js, Bootstrap, and d3.js

#### United (united.monstercat.com)

Sept. 2012

Web Promotion for Monstercat's United Album

- Utilized Google's Map API to displayed users geographical locations around the globe
- Featured a real-time, scrolling news feed and constantly updating map

#### **VOLUNTEERING**

#### Co-Chair

Feb. 2013 - Present

CNIB National Youth Council

- Developed new initiative to foster a sense of community and discussion in the Blind and Partially Sighted youth across Canada
- Organized the collection of resources relating to blind and partially signed youth with the goal of publishing these resources online

## Assistant Coach

Nov. 2008 - May 2010

Arnprior Amateur Wrestling Club, Arnprior, ON

- Planned and ran clinics for children (aged 4-12) to teach them the basics of Olympic freestyle wrestling
- Assisted head coach at junior and senior team practices and tournaments

# PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

## Summer Career Opportunity, Recreation and Education

July 2010

- S.C.O.R.E Program ran by the Canadian National Institute for the Blind
- Focused on personal development, team building, leadership and career skills and civic responsibility.
- Worked as part of a team to build strengths, actively practicing new skills, achieving goals with others

## PROGRAMMING INTERESTS

Functional Programming, Distributed Systems, Machine Learning